<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Food on jra&#39;s thoughts</title>
    <link>https://blog.nella.org/category/food/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Food on jra&#39;s thoughts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.147.8</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2012 19:50:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.nella.org/category/food/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Typically Swiss</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2012/10/19/918/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2012 19:50:04 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=918</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We love local products, so we love TerraSuisse. And we love their new advertisements:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Just Married</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2009/06/14/just-married/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2009 17:03:40 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=700</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been away from the web for a while because I was in Olivone, Ticino, Switzerland getting married!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to friends and family who came from so far away to witness such a special day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And thanks also to our wonderful vendors, who made the day go so well. If you are thinking of putting on a wedding in Blenio, give these guys a call:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.albergo-arcobaleno.ch/&#34;&gt;Restaurant/Hotel Arcobaleno&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.osteriacentraleolivone.ch/&#34;&gt;Osteria Centrale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.casalucomagno.ch/&#34;&gt;Casa Lucomagno&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.swissguide.ch/it/Forno/Olivone/1141813_panetteriaepasticceriabi.html&#34;&gt;Pasticceria Bini&lt;/a&gt; for wedding cakes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://designyou.ch&#34;&gt;Viva gli sposi&lt;/a&gt; wedding photojournalism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://tinyurl.com/giramondo&#34;&gt;Giramondo Travel Agency&lt;/a&gt; for the wedding registry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mx3.ch/artist/sonpalaria&#34;&gt;Sonpalaria&lt;/a&gt;, the heartbeat of the Ticinese dance floor!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It feels different to be married. It seems like it shouldn&amp;rsquo;t&amp;hellip; the house is the same, we still sleep on the same sides of the bed. But it&amp;rsquo;s different. Good. And safe. And happy. And&amp;hellip; different.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lemon Custard, or Curd, depending on your skill</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2009/04/24/lemon-custard-or-curd-depending-on-your-skill/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2009 19:48:02 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=650</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I used &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.celtnet.org.uk/recipes/miscellaneous/fetch-recipe.php?rid=misc-lemon-custard&#34;&gt;this recipe&lt;/a&gt; to make lemon custard. But I let it get too hot, so it curdled. So Mari got to sample Lemon Curd instead of Lemon Custard as intended. We liked it anyway!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hint to the reader (i.e. me if I come back to this next time I try it)&amp;hellip; you could reasonably start cooking the custard with direct heat, but you should finish it up over a bain marie, to prevent curdification.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two things I like about England</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2009/02/25/two-things-i-like-about-england/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2009 15:21:11 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=558</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been known to complain a bit, now and then, about my current hosts, the English. I reserve the right to continue complaining, to be sure, but I&amp;rsquo;d like to take a moment to point out two things I like about England:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://icicibank.co.uk/&#34;&gt;ICICI Bank UK&lt;/a&gt;: This is one of the largest banks in India. In England, they are a very little fish in a very big nasty pond. English banks are incredibly expensive, arrogant, rude, and customer unfriendly. But because ICICI is tiny, and because it is focused on a small niche (immigrants who are sending remittances home), it gives excellent service. Go ICICI! I love you!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Muffins: The English make very nice muffins. The chocolate/chocolate-chip ones are totally decadent, so when you want to take it easy, go for the ones which &lt;em&gt;merely&lt;/em&gt; have lemon curd inside and crystalized sugar on top.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS: The English also display enormous &lt;a href=&#34;http://images.google.com/images?q=muffintops&#34;&gt;muffin tops&lt;/a&gt;, but they are not really something you want to have&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Veg Box Blues (and Blacks)</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2009/01/28/veg-box-blues-and-blacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2009 20:27:41 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=531</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Marina and I are experimenting with what the Brits call a &amp;ldquo;veg box scheme&amp;rdquo;. Everything here is a scheme, but that&amp;rsquo;s a post for another day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the benefits/problems with veg boxes is that you never know what you are going to get. And you get stuff you might not have bought yourself. If you didn&amp;rsquo;t want it because you hate it, that&amp;rsquo;s a problem. But if you didn&amp;rsquo;t want it because you didn&amp;rsquo;t know what to do with it, that&amp;rsquo;s an &lt;strong&gt;opportunity&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indian Risotto</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2008/09/29/indian-risotto/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2008 18:23:08 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=294</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a tiny blurb about life in my new environment:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tesco is down the street. They are the UK&amp;rsquo;s largest supermarket chain, think Safeway in the US. Generic, filled with irritating British mothers and their unruly children, with prepared food as far as the eye can see and bad produce. (Good arugula though, I have to admit). Tonight Marina and I had our hearts set on risotto. And Tesco, with 500 types of frozen pastys, has only one brand of arborio rice. And it is out of stock.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
