<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Relief-Work on jra&#39;s thoughts</title>
    <link>https://blog.nella.org/category/relief-work/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Relief-Work on jra&#39;s thoughts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.147.8</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2009 11:29:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.nella.org/category/relief-work/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dealing with a clogged link</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2009/06/30/dealing-with-a-clogged-link/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2009 11:29:59 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=730</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A friend asked me a question that reminded me of some great resources I want to mention here (in case I ever need to find them again&amp;hellip;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://bwmo.net&#34;&gt;How to Accelerate Your Internet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://wndw.net&#34;&gt;Wireless Networking in the Developing World&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://wirelessu.org/&#34;&gt;Wireless U&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my response to my friend, I also touched on something interesting I learned from &lt;a href=&#34;http://cricket.sf.net&#34;&gt;Cricket&lt;/a&gt;, and from years as a consultant. Here&amp;rsquo;s the big lesson: &lt;strong&gt;Infrastructure projects don&amp;rsquo;t sell themselves.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>La promesse grippe - The Flu Code</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2009/04/30/la-promesse-grippe-the-flu-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2009 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=667</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Vinay Gupta published something called the &lt;a href=&#34;http://vinay.howtolivewiki.com/blog/personal/the-flu-code-ethical-behavior-to-protect-each-other-1435&#34;&gt;flu code&lt;/a&gt;. Here it is in French:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La promesse grippe 0.1Beta, version français – Une service dans l&amp;rsquo;intérêt publique de &lt;a href=&#34;http://collapsonomics.org/&#34;&gt;L&amp;rsquo;institute pour efrondnomiques&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Si j&amp;rsquo;ai des signes d&amp;rsquo;une grippe éventuel, je vais rester chez moi.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Je vais rester à distance des foules quand c&amp;rsquo;est possible, et je vais toujours porter une masque dans les lieux publiques.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Je vais laver les mains a la porte chaque fois je arrive a ma destination.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Je vais me engager de enseigner ces règles aux autres de protéger tous.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Economics of being a Hostage</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2009/04/23/the-economics-of-being-a-hostage/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2009 19:50:26 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=644</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s an incredible &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.npr.org/blogs/money/2009/04/pirates_have_timesheets.html&#34;&gt;inside view of the piracy business&lt;/a&gt;. What&amp;rsquo;s incredible is that NPR&amp;rsquo;s Channa Jaffe Walt managed to get a CEO of a shipping company on the phone and hear the inside story of the negotiations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what&amp;rsquo;s really interesting. The first thing the CEO says is, &amp;ldquo;I never thought for a moment that I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have to pay anything. The only question was how much, and when.&amp;rdquo; Channa asks him why and he says, &amp;ldquo;Look, there&amp;rsquo;s no one to turn to, we&amp;rsquo;re on our own out there and that&amp;rsquo;s all there is to it. You pay.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A long trip in Afghanistan</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2009/04/11/a-long-trip-in-afghanistan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2009 12:42:56 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=641</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://news.bbc.co.uk/2/hi/programmes/from_our_own_correspondent/7991937.stm&#34;&gt;This is an interesting story&lt;/a&gt; by a BBC correspondent, which pulls no punches. Easy to see why he was left feeling bitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two sides to every story of course, and I&amp;rsquo;m sure the military folks would tell you about security rules, zero tolerance for violation of force protection imperatives, risk asessments, etc, etc, etc. But that&amp;rsquo;s all missing the point. When you are doing counterinsurgency work, you have to be close to the people. You have to earn their respect by finding out what earns respect in their culture and then finding a way to &lt;strong&gt;do&lt;/strong&gt; it inside of your own culture. They, in turn, will come to know you and, if you deserve it, you&amp;rsquo;ll earn their respect in return.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My favorite things, all at once!</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2009/03/31/my-favorite-things-all-at-once/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2009 00:07:38 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=608</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yay for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.caida.org/~kc/&#34;&gt;old friends&lt;/a&gt;, economics, and technology! All at once!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;kc wrote a &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.caida.org/best_available_data/2009/03/29/icannrir-research-agenda-writ-large/&#34;&gt;blog posting with her humble ideas&lt;/a&gt; on how to use IP address space tax. Wait&amp;hellip; there&amp;rsquo;s a tax on address space? Yes, because it has become a scare quantity, because people are too lazy to move to IPv6, IPv4 address space is running out. The best of all bad ideas about what to do about this is to make an open market for address space, as though network addresses were some kind of useful piece of property with any kind of useful value. (BTW: When the present econolypse is over, and the next bubble starts, it will be an IPv4 address space bubble. Mark my words&amp;hellip;) Address space is bits. We can make more bits&amp;hellip; Look! I just made some! But because the value of a network exists in everyone who is using it, not just &lt;strong&gt;your&lt;/strong&gt; implementation of the network, you can&amp;rsquo;t just add bits in your IP stack and get any benefit. So, while bits are free, and address space could conceiveably be free, because we have a network with limited space, we have a scarce asset. And, of course, what do humans do with scarce assets? We make bubbles! Yay for bubbles!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The New Yorker on Aid Work</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2009/01/09/the-new-yorker-on-aid-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2009 15:22:16 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=464</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is a really excellent &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.newyorker.com/reporting/2009/01/05/090105fa_fact_harr?printable=true&#34;&gt;article on aid work&lt;/a&gt; in The New Yorker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though this is pretty much a write-only blog at this point, and I don&amp;rsquo;t really know if anyone cares, here are my reactions to the article:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is remarkably candid, but&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it is too hopeless&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;because it focuses too much on the UN and not enough on independent actors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, any reader of mine know my biases: I am a cynical humanist capitalist from Silicon Valley (engaged to be married to a practical humanist socialist from Switzerland), who chose to work with MSF due to it&amp;rsquo;s independence. Because this article speaks to the core of my identity, of course my biases are going to be the key to my understanding of it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Malaria Medicine Advice</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2008/12/13/malaria-medicine-advice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2008 16:01:02 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=446</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A friend sent me this question:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of healthy, when you&amp;rsquo;re in Africa, do you take malaria medication the whole time you&amp;rsquo;re there? Is 45 days too long to take it?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, taking it 45 days is no big deal. It&amp;rsquo;s taking it for months on end (9, 18, 60) that is not recommended &amp;ndash; not because of actual risks, but because of not enough study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, here&amp;rsquo;s Jeff&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;cut-through-the-crap&amp;rdquo; guide to malaria meds:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HQ folks: Don&#39;t Do This</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2008/10/31/hq-folks-dont-do-this/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2008 16:19:12 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=416</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hopping on the meme-wagon for a second here&amp;hellip; if you care enough, read these three posts about paper pushing in the NGO world:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://alannashaikh.blogspot.com/2008/10/this-job-is-not-always-fun.html&#34;&gt;This Job Is Not Always Fun&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.owen.org/blog/106&#34;&gt;De-escalating the paperwork in development&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.humanitarian.info/2008/10/31/kill-your-reports/&#34;&gt;Kill Your Reports&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the last one, Paul considers what happens after the reports make it to HQ, from the point of view of field people:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;it seems there is no such impact. Country offices receive little or no feedback on their reports, and individual staff receive none. It&amp;rsquo;s also hard to identify any link between the reports that are generated in-country and any strategic decision-making, although it&amp;rsquo;s clear that there is some benefit there.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Search of Deviants</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2008/10/27/in-search-of-deviants/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2008 13:03:49 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=405</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://bloodandmilk.org/2008/05/22/things-i-believe-in-1-positive-deviance/&#34;&gt;Positive Deviance&lt;/a&gt; is a somewhat unnecessarily complicated name for something deeply humane and useful:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In every village, there is at least one woman (usually a few) whose children are healthier than the rest. For whatever reason, that woman is better at navigating the complexities of village life and child nutrition. That woman has knowledge and skills which can be taught. You find her, you learn from her, you support her to teach her peers. That is positive deviance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>With all due respect Mr Holmes...</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2008/10/23/with-all-due-respect-mr-holmes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2008 15:36:20 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=394</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You can kiss my ass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talking about the risks faced by humanitarian workers, you &lt;a href=&#34;http://news.bbc.co.uk/2/hi/7681604.stm&#34;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People in this business have always accepted the risks, there have always been losses, there have always been horrific incidents&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is NO SUCH THING as acceptable losses for humanitarian aid. Period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS: I noticed that, &lt;a href=&#34;http://ochaonline.un.org/AboutOCHA/Organigramme/TheUnderSecretaryGeneral/tabid/1154/language/en-US/Default.aspx&#34;&gt;according to your bio&lt;/a&gt;, you&amp;rsquo;ve never even worked in the field. So please do not count my life and the lives of my colleages as &amp;ldquo;acceptable losses&amp;rdquo;. Thanks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shame and Aid Work</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2008/10/13/shame-and-aid-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2008 17:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=367</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://humanitarianrelief.change.org/blog/view/bonjour_monsieur_-_what_to_do_when_rebels_overrun_your_compound&#34;&gt;This&lt;/a&gt; is a story a bit like mine from Chad, though we were not faced with bandits/rebels/soldiers directly. The feelings of shame and regret she has are related to the complicated feelings I had on leaving Chad as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my case, we had nothing to be ashamed of &amp;ndash; we took good care of ourselves and our staff and were not bad guests anywhere. But it does give you a sense of shame that as an expat you are different: you&amp;rsquo;re allowed to just go away, and your colleagues can&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When Not In Control, People Imagine Order</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2008/10/13/when-not-in-control-people-imagine-order/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2008 10:04:22 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=365</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Science Friday did an &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sciencefriday.com/program/archives/200810037&#34;&gt;interesting story recently&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New research shows that when people perceive they have no control over a given situation, they are more likely to see illusions, patterns where none exist and even believe in conspiracy theories. The study suggests that people impose imaginary order when no real order can be perceived.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first caller reports on how the conditions he experienced working as an aid worker in Somalia showed this. Also, he comments on the rough ride back to normality after suffering a situation with loss of control.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NSA is Spying on MSF</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2008/10/10/nsa-is-spying-on-msf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2008 10:29:36 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=347</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.salon.com/opinion/greenwald/2008/10/09/eavesdropping/&#34;&gt;story&lt;/a&gt; that&amp;rsquo;s, unfortunately, not a surprise:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KINNE: And over the course of my time, as we slowly began to identify phone numbers and who belonged to what, one thing that gave me grave concern was that as we identified phone numbers, we started to find more and more and more numbers that belonged not to any organizations affiliated with terrorism or with military &amp;hellip; with militaries of Iraq or Afghanistan or elsewhere, but with humanitarian aid organizations, non-governmental organizations, who include the International Red Cross, Red Crescent, &lt;strong&gt;Doctors Without Borders&lt;/strong&gt;, a whole host of humanitarian aid organizations. And it also included journalists&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Same conversation, different venue</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2008/10/09/same-conversation-different-venue/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2008 12:53:14 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=343</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The dirty secret of aid work&amp;hellip; it always comes down to this&amp;hellip; the navel-gazing, &amp;ldquo;why am I here&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;why is it so ineffective&amp;rdquo; conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usually it happens around the campfire, over a bottle of locally made beer, or perhaps for the lucky coordination team in the capital city, at the nearby expat-only restaurant over a nice bottle of South African wine. As with everything this century, it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aidworkers.net/?q=node/1604&#34;&gt;moved onto the Internet&lt;/a&gt;. But the essential tone of the conversation, and the impossibility of resolving the problem remains.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Morning Coffee Notes</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2008/10/02/morning-coffee-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2008 08:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=312</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With apologies to Dave for the title&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This morning I see that Jon over at &lt;a href=&#34;http://AidWorkerDaily.com&#34;&gt;AidWorkerDaily.com&lt;/a&gt; has added his ideas to my article there, and asked me to comment. I did, go read it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I was researching stuff for my reply, I stumbled across these resources on African IT that I&amp;rsquo;m going to start following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://appfrica.net/blog/&#34;&gt;Appfrica&lt;/a&gt;: African IT, Industry News and Culture&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://google-africa.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;Google Africa&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crowd control in Ethiopia</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2008/10/01/crowd-control-in-ethiopia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2008 10:10:49 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=309</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My major job in Ethiopia this summer was crowd control. As a log, I am responsible for setting up the facilities where we work &amp;ndash; a little bit of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pioneeringmadeeasy.co.uk/bridges/susbridgefrench.html&#34;&gt;pioneering merit badge&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://goo.gl/photos/A1qLju91NNxJa2pA6&#34;&gt;architecture&lt;/a&gt;, and a whole lot of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.usafe.af.mil/shared/media/photodb/photos/060623-f-3366c-005.JPG&#34;&gt;crowd control&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are two pictures from MSF&amp;rsquo;s interventions in Ethiopia that give you an idea of what my job looked like: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.msf.fr/slideshow.php?related=82&amp;amp;ids=15&#34;&gt;the lines&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.msf.fr/slideshow.php?related=82&amp;amp;ids=16&#34;&gt;talking to mothers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MSF training didn&amp;rsquo;t prepare me for crowd control, which is too bad. There are some simple principles, and learning them by trial and error is dangerous and not very much fun (not for the log, not for the medical team, and especially not for the beneficiaries). The basic principle is &amp;ldquo;calm people are safe, scared people are dangerous&amp;rdquo;. Everything else follows from there. Keep people informed, and set up your site so that even if they don&amp;rsquo;t understand or can&amp;rsquo;t hear the verbal instructions, they can see what&amp;rsquo;s happening and be confident that they are waiting for something of value, and that it won&amp;rsquo;t run out before they get it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Very Happy New Year News</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2008/02/03/very-happy-new-year-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2008 12:30:20 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=283</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello everybody, and happy new years. 2008 is going to be really great for me, I have some news to share here to get all those who are interested in my travels back up to date with my life and my plans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://picasaweb.google.com/jeff.allen/Marina/photo#5038569798669660322&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://lh5.google.com/jeff.allen/ReyYiVG3cKI/AAAAAAAAAEc/-hwBDymULFI/s144/DSC07083.JPG&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; First, the most important thing in my whole life&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;ve finally found the perfect girl for me. Her name is Marina, and we&amp;rsquo;ve been together over a year now. She and I weren&amp;rsquo;t ready to talk so publicly about our relationship until now, but now the time has come, so that&amp;rsquo;s the first really great piece of news for the blog in 2008.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hello from Belgium</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2007/10/27/hello-from-belgium/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2007 11:13:32 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=279</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello again after a long time away from writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I wrote last, I took a nice trip around the west coast, then hung around California doing some IT work. Then I moved to Lausanne, Switzerland where I studied French for two months for 4.5 hours a day. I also enjoyed riding my bike a lot, up to 200 km a week, through the Swiss countryside. I moved to Geneva and stayed with friends there during September and some of October. I volunteered at MSF Switzerland&amp;rsquo;s headquarters, doing special projects for the Logistics department there and continuing my French with a private tutor.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Look at Field Life for Tool Makers</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2007/08/14/a-look-at-field-life-for-tool-makers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2007 04:41:07 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=276</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have recently been talking with some folks about IT tools for humanitarian aid workers. I gave a real-world reality check to them, not to discourage them, but to make sure they knew their audience as well as possible. After all, what good is a tool that looks good in demos, but fails with the users? A good step towards avoiding abject failure is to sit with your users and watch them work. That&amp;rsquo;s not so easy with humanitarian field workers. A tolerable substitute is to collect testimonies from them with the same kind of data, and try to design a system that has a chance of working in the context.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#34;squat toilets &#43; leaping cockroaches = unhappy expats&#34;</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2007/04/23/squat-toilets-leaping-cockroaches-unhappy-expats/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2007 23:42:39 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=275</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.msf.ca/blogs&#34;&gt;great blogs&lt;/a&gt; at MSF Canada. The quote in the title came from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.msf.ca/blogs/JuliaP.php?itemid=177&#34;&gt;Made in Bangladesh&lt;/a&gt; by Julia Payson. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.msf.ca/blogs/JamesM.php&#34;&gt;James Maskalyk&lt;/a&gt; is also writing sublime postings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My mom asked me, &amp;ldquo;How come MSF Canada&amp;rsquo;s volunteers get to blog and you couldn&amp;rsquo;t?&amp;rdquo; The answer is just a matter of comfort level with the new medium. Like all organizations have in the last few years, MSF is currently digesting what blogs mean and how they can be used. It is not much of a surprise to me that MSF Canada, some of whose volunteers work at MSF Holland, would be ahead of the curve on this one. Canada is a small place full of curious people. Of course they are going to experiment with blogs!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hello Pandang, Indonesia</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2007/03/15/hello-pandang-indonesia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2007 21:15:39 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=271</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So I have neglected to write an update for a very long time. Here&amp;rsquo;s a tiny update to give you a taste of things to come in the next few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got back from Morocco and settled into my home away from home in Switzerland. I met Marina, a former coworker from MSF who I met in Liberia. We traveled around Switzerland seeing old friends of hers. I practiced some Italian, went cross country skiing, and spent quite a while sick as a dog from a stupid cold I got in Ticino.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Liberian Civil Servants</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2007/01/04/liberian-civil-servants/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2007 07:03:26 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=266</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;office&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://www.aidg.org/images/blog/liber20_civil_servant.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.foreignpolicy.com/story/cms.php?story_id=3502&amp;amp;page=0&#34;&gt;This photo essay&lt;/a&gt; shows pictures of several Liberian civil servants. The picture of the governor of River Gee brought back memories. I met village chiefs in offices like this to talk about how MSF could work with the community.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Handover</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2006/12/07/handover/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=264</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It has been a long time since I wrote last, so here is a tiny update. I am doing the handover to the new November 2 right now. It is a very strange thing to have him here and be able to literally count the days. Also now I have to pay particular attention to issues of respect, authority, control, and so on. I need my staff to see that this is an orderly transition and that I trust and have confidence in the new guy so that they do too. It is a different set of things to think about, but not too hard to figure out.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quiplu can&#39;t count to four</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2006/11/21/quiplu-cant-count-to-four/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=263</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of our cars is broken. The differential was making noise. In Liberian English, car parts can be &amp;ldquo;fine&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;not fine&amp;rdquo;, or &amp;ldquo;finished&amp;rdquo;. The mechanic took it apart this morning and found that one of the bearings in this differential is finished. It was interesting to see the insides of the differential, and I spent a while poking at it on the workbench, and having the mechanic explain the finer points to me (&amp;ldquo;This can spin, but those don&amp;rsquo;t so they have dicks and not bearings. Dicks, yes, dicks. Discs? No, dicks. And these, they can&amp;rsquo;t spoil too easy. You put different spacers in like so when these are not too fine, but you can&amp;rsquo;t file the spacers yourself, you have to get them from Toyota.&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Busy and also not so busy</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2006/11/18/busy-and-also-not-so-busy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=262</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We were really busy here in October because of the need to plan 2007&amp;rsquo;s activities. We had to make a Plan of Action, then we had to make the budget. The whole process was eye opening into how MSF plans its activities, and working on the budget was sometimes boring drudge work, but sometimes it was really interesting. I understand the MSF budget system much better now, and in the future I will be able to quickly see what work was envisioned by the previous people when I get to a new project. I put in a bunch of nifty things that I think the next log/admin will appreciate, including major repairs to the radios and some replacement equipment for stuff we have worn out.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I don&#39;t know what I&#39;m going to get, but it&#39;ll be fine</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2006/10/31/i-dont-know-what-im-going-to-get-but-itll-be-fine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2006 12:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=261</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I just had the most profound sense of peace wash over me&amp;hellip; not of the spiritual variety, but of the logistical. I was out checking up on the carpenters to make sure they understood my instructions right and were building the right stuff today. I held the plank for the guy as he was sawing out the handle for the drawer he is making. I puzzled for a while about the two pieces he was making, trying to figure out how he&amp;rsquo;d make a handle out of them. Then it dawned on me, &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t know what he&amp;rsquo;s going to make, but I&amp;rsquo;m sure it will be fine.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Birthday wishes from the WFP</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2006/10/23/birthday-wishes-from-the-wfp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2006 17:54:12 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=260</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just a quick note to tell you all that I had a great birthday here in Nimba. The day went much better than could be expected, starting with the surprise arrival of the chief mechanic who fixed three cars today. It was not really a surprise, but it sort of felt like it, because he arrived on Saturday when I wasn&amp;rsquo;t around, and then came in to work on Monday morning and started waving his magic wrench around like a fairy sprinkling motor oil and fixing cars.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Back at work</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2006/10/22/back-at-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2006 21:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=259</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week was a regular work week for me, but a couple days were shaved off it while I was in transit back to Nimba. It has been nice to get back to the normal schedule of Nimba life. None of the normal annoyances really bugged me because I was happy to be back &amp;ldquo;home&amp;rdquo;. I started looking forward to the second half of my time here and realized that because I took my break a little late, the second half is actually only 7 weeks or so. And it was a strange feeling indeed to imagine that that won&amp;rsquo;t be enough time to get everything done. When I got here, the 6 months seemed like an eternity, but once I figured out how to keep the trains running on time I realized how little time there is for new work. And how few months to get it done in.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hello from Nimba again</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2006/10/18/hello-from-nimba-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2006 21:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=258</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am back in Nimba now, back with my adopted family here. The work is hard (even just one day has already presented a terrifying array of problems), but I am really happy to be back with the team and in my &amp;ldquo;own&amp;rdquo; bed. I brought back a new expat from Monrovia with me. Pierre is a Frenchman, an architect who worked in San Francisco for several years, and returned to France, then quit his job to work on real problems, instead of the somewhat unreal ones that architecture offered. He said that it annoyed him that people designed buildings that they do not know how to make. I don&amp;rsquo;t know yet if he knows how to make buildings, but I really like him and I think he will do well. His job is to build the replacement building for the pole and plastic sheeting hospital that I am supposed to keep limping along.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m still alive</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2006/10/01/im-still-alive/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2006 23:35:12 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=255</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just a quick note to tell you all that I am still alive. Things have not been super busy, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t felt too much like writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week a logistics helper came from Monrovia and completed a renovation of the building that used to be our food store into a new office building. After we finish moving out of the office this week, we will have more bedrooms for both the new expat arriving soon, and for guests. Right now, there are no rooms in the inn. I kept the rehabilitation plans really simple in order to get them done fast. I had planned to leave the wood trim unpainted and only whitewash the walls. But it turned out that we had some white paint left over from the health post renovation at Lepula. So I gave the team that paint to use. Then they complained that you can&amp;rsquo;t paint the walls white and the trim white. Fashion nazis! So we dug around some more and found some Jade Green paint that was also incorrectly bought for Lepula. Ministry of Health standard for health posts in Liberia is whitewashed walls with Forest Green trim, so the Jade Green was right out. I gave them that to mix with the white. The result is a shade of green that reminds me of the United States Forest Service every time I see it. Everyone really likes the new office because of the green windows and doors. They are pretty snazzy, actually.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ER</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2006/09/19/er/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2006 09:02:24 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=254</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Twice now, we&amp;rsquo;ve gotten huge numbers of injured people from vehicle accidents. Things are difficult in a hospital made of poles and plastic sheeting in the best of times, but with an influx of 15 to 20 injured people at night, it can get ugly fast. Luckily Emir (our doctor) is really good at handling situations like that. The team works together really well, and we all know our specialties well and how to anticipate problems, so it&amp;rsquo;s exciting, but not utter pandemonium,&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Jeff is BRAVE!&#34;</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2006/09/15/jeff-is-brave/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2006 23:58:36 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=253</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today we had a little excitement in the compound. The storekeeper came to me really agitated. He said that he&amp;rsquo;d gone in the food store to check that things were ready to deliver food on Monday. But when he opened the door he found a big snake. He showed me that it was as big as his forearm. Now, we have snake scares from time to time. It results in a frenzy of activity, as all the expats run for digital cameras, and the Liberians who grew up in the bush get their slingshots, cutlasses and sharp sticks ready, and all the city boys from Monrovia scream like girls. I tend to try to steer clear of the circus and watch the country boys to make sure that the snake is dispatched swiftly and safely.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toys for TFC</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2006/09/12/toys-for-tfc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2006 23:24:08 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=252</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The TFC is the Therapeutic Feeding Center, where severely malnourished patients can be fattened up. This is significantly harder than it sounds since it turns out that human bodies do not take well to severe starvation. As you put in fluids and carbohydrates, the body needs to adjust and deal with the new chemical balances. You can kill a person by feeding them. So the medicine in the TFC is actually a specialty, like urology or proctology, but less icky. Unfortunately for all the malnourished people in Africa, it is also a rare specialty, so we here in Saclepea are just sort of doing our best to run the TFC according to the books the experts in Europe wrote and sent to us. There&amp;rsquo;s a certain amount of &amp;ldquo;if it works, don&amp;rsquo;t change it&amp;rdquo;, which is OK, but can be dangerous if things aren&amp;rsquo;t actually working, but you don&amp;rsquo;t understand what&amp;rsquo;s happening enough to be able to tell.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning the Lingo</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2006/09/03/learning-the-lingo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2006 15:36:48 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=251</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello from the middle of a huge rainstorm. It has been threatening to rain all day, and getting muggier and muggier, so it is nice that the rain and the cool breezes have finally come. It means, of course, that when I am done writing this and try to send it, it will fail because the satellite signal is blocked, but this is a small inconvenience to trade for the cool breeze coming through the office.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Priorities</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2006/08/23/priorities/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2006 20:44:19 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=250</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been quite busy here recently and my energy level is flagging because a Sunday that was supposed to be restful ended having several fire drills in it, so the whole team pretty much missed a day of rest. We have 4 guests here right now from Swiss Development Corporation, so they take a bit of attention. But luckily, tomorrow is Flag Day, a Liberian holiday, so we get an extra day off.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Rainy Sunday</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2006/08/13/a-rainy-sunday/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2006 16:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=249</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t mentioned the weather here much yet, but today weather dominated my activities, so I have it on the mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I first got to Monrovia a month and a half ago, I was welcomed back to the tropics by the heat and humidity I had become used to in the Peten, in northeastern Guatemala. As we were on the ocean in Monrovia, we got nice breezes, and the temperature was quite mild. But still it was the kind of heat and humidity that makes you sweaty just five minutes after a shower.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The MSF farm</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2006/08/02/the-msf-farm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2006 01:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=247</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The rules say you aren&amp;rsquo;t supposed to have any pets in the expat house so that there&amp;rsquo;s no problem with allergies or fleas. But rules were meant to be broken.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our compound has: one dog, one cat, one hen with three Guinea fowl chicks as big as it, another hen with 9 chicks, 2 roosters (well, on Saturday we had two, read on to find out their fate), and two goats (like the roosters, this statistic is now out of date). In case someone from headquarters in Geneva is reading this, I would hasten to add that these are not pets but &amp;ldquo;program resources for maintenance of employee morale&amp;rdquo;. Are the bean-counters gone yet? OK, I can tell you about all our pets then&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What we do on a holiday</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2006/07/27/what-we-do-on-a-holiday/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2006 12:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=246</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I got lots of stuff done on my &amp;ldquo;day off&amp;rdquo; yesterday due to the Liberian Independence Day. The threat of unrest on a national holiday meant that we were confined to the compound all day while the staff had the day off. Even though I had a day off to catch up, I had a really hectic morning with a thousand little problems to solve. The most embarrassing one is that we ran out of rice for the hospital. Last week we ran out of tea, which was a big crisis because the staff is so touchy about missing a tea break. Running out of rice and tea were basically both squarely my fault, but each time they were easy to fix, and I&amp;rsquo;m confident that we&amp;rsquo;ve got things set up right for August.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A little excitement</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2006/07/23/a-little-excitement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2006 15:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=245</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I sat down to do my Sunday blog posting at about 10 pm but was immediately interrupted by our night watchman. He came to me to tell me that the hospital staff had an UNMIL (UN Mission in Liberia) vehicle there asking MSF staff to go with them out into the night to fetch an injured patient from the site of a motorcycle accident halfway to Tappita. I knew we probably couldn&amp;rsquo;t do it, because it breaks several rules (staff don&amp;rsquo;t leave the hospital to treat patients, we don&amp;rsquo;t travel at night, and we don&amp;rsquo;t ride in UNMIL vehicles), but I went and got a second opinion from the field coordinator, who is the most senior person on site. She agreed, so I had to give the hospital alternative instructions: give UNMIL dressings for one patient and instructions on how to stabilize them and transport them. I also got the guards on the radio and reminded them of their responsibilities with respect to UNMIL, which is that their vehicles must stay outside the hospital gates, no matter how insistent the driver or how urgent the situation seems. MSF staff may go out and carry in any patient that UNMIL drops off (no questions asked; it could be a soldier, as long as he&amp;rsquo;s unarmed). The watchmen know the drill, but emergencies get people excited, and sometimes people forget rules. I figured it was better for the voice of reason to remind them of the rules than to have someone make a bad decision and then have people talking tomorrow about how the new log lets UNMIL come in the hospital.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A day in the life of a log</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2006/07/16/a-day-in-the-life-of-a-log/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2006 05:16:18 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=244</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I figured I should give people an idea what exactly a logistician does. The glib answer is that we do everything the medical team either cannot or do not want to do. But actually in this project, at this time, it is a combination of upper management (meetings and signatures on slips of paper) and construction planning and management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I get up each work day at 6:45 am. I spend 15 minutes or so getting awake, and then I meet my assistant and chat about how the day is going to go. The drivers are arriving at 7 am and getting their vehicles ready. Sometimes they arrive late, so they are put away dirty, so there are people washing cars, checking oil and other fluids, etc. The stock keeper, who is responsible for the fuel store, is fueling vehicles. Once I have a general idea that things are going according to plan and which vehicles will be ready to work that day, I head in to share breakfast with the team.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My first week in Nimba</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2006/07/09/my-first-week-in-nimba/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2006 06:14:14 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=243</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, I survived my first week as the log/admin for the Nimba project!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The big event this week was me taking over financial responsibility for the safes and all the cash in the project. At the same time, I also helped close the books for June. We had a troublesome 281 USD to track down, but thanks to my training in Geneva, which happened to cover the precise tricky bit accounting we were having trouble with, I got it fixed. Of course, the majority of the work to prepare for closing the books was done by my assistant, Mr. Toe. He brings me the books ready to go, and I review them. He tried his hardest to get them to balance, but this time it was up to me to find the remaining errors.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Made it to Nimba County</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2006/07/02/made-it-to-nimba-county/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2006 01:23:05 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=242</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On Friday, Jerome and I made the drive up to Nimba County. We took 2 patients, their 2 caregivers, and a baby. In Africa, hospitals budget for two people for every admitted patient. The second person is a caregiver, who is responsible for feeding and washing the patient. This doubles the amount of logistical needs related to patients (food, transport, etc) but it dramatically reduces the per-patient workload of the skilled nursing labor, which means the few nurses the countries have go farther. But the downside is that the families are more profoundly disrupted by someone going to the hospital, since typically the wife/mother is the caregiver. That means the older children at home have to do the work their mom was doing (gathering firewood, farming, doing the laundry) which may mean they leave school temporarily. So you can see that the ripple effects go out and out when MSF decides to admit a patient.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heading out to Nimba</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2006/06/30/heading-out-to-nimba/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2006 02:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=241</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today Jerome (outreach nurse in the Nimba project) and I are heading out to Nimba. The roads are in good shape, so it is only a 6 hour drive. We drive halfway and meet a car coming from the other direction. We transfer ourselves, our two patients, their two caregivers, and our cargo over to the other Land Cruiser. Then each car returns to it&amp;rsquo;s own base. That way each base only loses a vehicle for one day, instead of one base losing a vehicle for two days and one night.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My first few days in Monrovia</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2006/06/26/my-first-few-days-in-monrovia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2006 11:58:01 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=240</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey, just a quick update to let you all know I got to Monrovia safely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arriving in Roberts International Airport was an interesting experience. First, the runway could use a paving job, so while the landing was perfect the deceleration part of the flight was a bit hair-raising, even for someone like me who doesn&amp;rsquo;t worry much about flying. Then as we taxied off the runway and almost immediately came to a stop, we passed about a million UN planes. They really gave me the &amp;ldquo;we&amp;rsquo;re not in Kansas, Toto&amp;rdquo; feeling! Getting through passport control and customs was very easy, but then all my baggage had MSF logos on it, and I was wearing my MSF t-shirt. I&amp;rsquo;m told it helps immensely with customs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Got to Monrovia</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2006/06/26/got-to-monrovia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2006 01:43:54 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=239</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just a quick update to let you all know that I have arrived safely in Monrovia. We rode in from the airport last night in an MSF Land Cruiser through an evening rainstorm. The weather here is comfortable&amp;hellip; it is quite hot and humid, but not as bad as Mississippi or Guatemala was. The tropical rainstorms are strong, warm, and short, so they are easy to deal with. My room is comfortable, with a nice mosquito net and screens on the windows.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This one goes out to all the proud moms out there...</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2006/06/24/this-one-goes-out-to-all-the-proud-moms-out-there/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2006 03:57:07 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=238</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nella.org/img/jra-msf.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;jra in msf shirt&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://www.nella.org/img/jrs-msf-sm.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Click for a huge version suitable for printing and fridge posting.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wrapping things up here in Geneva. I&amp;rsquo;m staying the night with Sima and Steve, and they are dropping me off at the airport tomorrow morning at 7 am. I fly through Brussels, Dakar, and then I arrive at Roberts Field outside of Monrovia about 6 pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll send an update from MSF&amp;rsquo;s office in Monrovia in the next couple of days.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Life in Geneva - La vie genevois</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2006/06/22/life-in-geneva-la-vie-genevois/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2006 02:02:51 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=237</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am currently in Geneva for my briefings. I&amp;rsquo;ve been having fun in the evenings with friends from the old days at Bunyip in Montreal, Steve and Sima. During the day, I go around meeting people and getting verbal briefings, and doing self-study with various materials. Yesterday my biggest problem was that I was overwhelmed with reference material and couldn&amp;rsquo;t figure out what to look at.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far I&amp;rsquo;ve had a &amp;ldquo;general advice&amp;rdquo; briefing from Kath in New York, a meeting with the PR guys in New York (they are getting these updates; Hi Michelle and Michael!), a meeting about the political and program context in West Africa, a meeting about the purchasing system, and a briefing on how the IT and communications stuff works. My temporary office is in the logistics department, so I&amp;rsquo;m learning from them by osmosis, but I still need to make time to talk to some of the subject matter experts in detail, like how to maintain Nimba&amp;rsquo;s water system, what to know about the generators in use in Liberia, and how to maintain the fleet of vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What I&#39;ve been up to</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2006/06/17/what-ive-been-up-to/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2006 15:36:07 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=236</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During the last two weeks I&amp;rsquo;ve been pretty busy. I worked for a week at International Medical Corps in Santa Monica. During that time I spent a lot of time with a new mentor, Jon Thompson. He and his wife have worked in Liberia, and it was partly them that gave me the confidence to accept the posting with MSF.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the week I visited old college friends in Los Angeles, then I drove back up to Redwood City (6 hours). I spent the afternoon and evening doing errands. The next day I drove to Roseburg (9 hours). I visited with family there. Mom made a great combination congratulations and bon voyage meal. The next morning I drove to Portland and commenced work on the Humaninet Simulation Day event.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Off I go to Liberia</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2006/06/08/off-i-go-to-liberia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2006 03:06:24 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=235</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I got my posting! And so the real adventure begins&amp;hellip; the rest of this has just been academic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll be working as a &amp;ldquo;log-admin&amp;rdquo; in an MSF-Switzerland project based on Saclepea, Nimba County, Liberia. The log part of my job is making sure things go smoothly so the programs keep running. The admin part of my job will be to handle paying salaries and keeping the books.
My contract is for six months.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where&#39;s Jeff?</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2006/06/04/wheres-jeff/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2006 23:23:33 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=234</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sorry I haven&amp;rsquo;t sent out an update in a while. I&amp;rsquo;ve been visiting family and doing paperwork to get in the MSF system. I got my medical clearance from my doctor, extra eye glasses, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kat the Dog and I traveled up to Oregon to see my parents and grandparents. A consulting job back in the Silicon Valley fell through, so Kat and I continued north to Seattle where we helped prepare my step-brother&amp;rsquo;s house to be sold. Good thing too, because he &lt;strong&gt;bought&lt;/strong&gt; a new house while we were there!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m an MSF volunteer now!</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2006/05/01/im-an-msf-volunteer-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2006 18:52:17 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=233</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I got the letter from MSF in New York today, and I have been entered into their pool of available volunteers! This is what I&amp;rsquo;ve been working towards for over a year, and I&amp;rsquo;m really happy! As well as the good kind of scared you get when ambitious tasks present themselves to you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next step is an orientation in New York City, and the process of finding the right first posting for me. I&amp;rsquo;ll learn more about that process in the coming week, probably. Because the final decision on deploying me is out of their hands, the New York office can&amp;rsquo;t really guess when I&amp;rsquo;ll be deployed. However, the fact that I have very few limitations on the timeframe or location of my posting means I&amp;rsquo;ll be considered for more postings than some other first timers will be.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My interview with MSF</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2006/04/12/my-interview-with-msf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2006 23:55:58 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=231</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I had my interview with MSF. It went pretty well, I think. I was well prepared, both for the interview and for the multiple choice test they give logisticians. In the interview I got a number of chances to explain how I think my past experiences will help me do the job. Molly asked me how I&amp;rsquo;d deal with the inevitable problems of close team living, and I had an answer that I think pleased her.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Woofer for hire!</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2006/04/04/woofer-for-hire/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2006 21:24:36 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=230</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just in time for my upcoming MSF interview, I&amp;rsquo;ve finished my WFR (pronounced &amp;ldquo;woofer&amp;rdquo;) certification. I don&amp;rsquo;t know if my interviewer will ask about first aid skills, but I can guarantee you that I&amp;rsquo;ll find a way to tell her! I&amp;rsquo;m really proud of this certification, not just because of the skills it gives me in case I need to provide emergency care for a colleague someplace remote, but because it shows I have taken the initiative to continue preparing myself for my chosen career. You wouldn&amp;rsquo;t think, while working with doctors and nurses, that you&amp;rsquo;d need to know medicine, but Jon told me a story from his MSF days that made me decide to get the WFR training. He found himself in a situation where he was the best hope half a dozen meningitis patients had to survive the next 24 hours&amp;hellip; as he said, &amp;ldquo;it&amp;rsquo;s not supposed to work that way, but sometimes it does&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wilderness First Responder in the making</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2006/03/26/wilderness-first-responder-in-the-making/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2006 23:01:02 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=229</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t posted in a while. I&amp;rsquo;ve been hanging around the Bay Area. I did a contract for my old boss at his &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.metaweb.com&#34;&gt;new employer&lt;/a&gt;, and some other random undirected hanging out I can&amp;rsquo;t really remember. Oh, I think it involved postponing writing code by taking the dog to the dog park. I&amp;rsquo;ve also been working on the unread books from my bibliography, including some new ones I found. One is really gripping; it is a memoir of a Canadian nurse who worked for MSF for four years. So much of what she says is familiar to me after all my reading.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Got an MSF interview!</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2006/03/12/got-an-msf-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2006 11:49:52 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=228</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some great news on the relief work job hunt: I got a phone call from MSF USA the other day to set up an interview. It will be on April 12, here in San Francisco. The nice lady from MSF told me that what made the difference were recommendations I got from ex-MSF volunteers. Thanks &lt;a href=&#34;http://hlink.org/&#34;&gt;Jon&lt;/a&gt; and Amy!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A humanitarian aid bibliography</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2006/03/09/a-humanitarian-aid-bibliography/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2006 00:26:38 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=227</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a list of the books I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading over the last year and a half as I figure out how the relief world works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/1401352014/jrasthought-20&#34;&gt;Emergency Sex and Other Desperate Measures&lt;/a&gt;. A sometimes funny, sometimes scathing, sometimes touching story of three aid workers working in the UN system in the 90&amp;rsquo;s. Will not leave a good taste in your mouth for the UN, or in fact, for some of the characters. But they get points for honesty, I guess.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0684856530/jrasthought-20&#34;&gt;Triage&lt;/a&gt;, a well written novella about a terrible story of PTSD (post traumatic stress disorder)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0385486650/jrasthought-20&#34;&gt;The Man Who Tried to Save the World: The dangerous life and mysterious disappearence of Fred Cuny&lt;/a&gt;. An profile of a legendary aid worker, and of his mysterious death in Chechnya. This book made me strike Chechnya from the places I would accept a job. (Well, the book and the fact I don&amp;rsquo;t even read Cyrillic, so I&amp;rsquo;d be useless there.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/068480977X/jrasthought-20&#34;&gt;A Bed for the Night: Humanitarianism in Crisis&lt;/a&gt;. A careful look at mistakes made and how to move forward. Pays special attention to the problem of the &amp;ldquo;humanitarian-military complex&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0312243359/jrasthought-20&#34;&gt;We Wish to Inform You That Tomorrow We Will be Killed With Our Families: Stories from Rwanda&lt;/a&gt;. The best book to understand the genocide in Rwanda. Nothing good comes of reading this book, you just feel sad and empty. Perhaps the only good that can come from it is educating people so that it never happens again. But clearly that&amp;rsquo;s not happening, since it&amp;rsquo;s happening right now, again, in Sudan.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/157075487X/jrasthought-20&#34;&gt;Another Day in Paradise: International Humanitarian Workers Tell Their Stories&lt;/a&gt;. Does a really good job of letting aid workers speak in their own words about their motivations. Understanding your own motivation is key to being effective, I&amp;rsquo;m told. Hint: &amp;ldquo;I just want to help&amp;rdquo; isn&amp;rsquo;t going to get you through the hard days.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/1853395218/jrasthought-20&#34;&gt;Engineering in Emergencies : A Practical Guide for Relief Workers&lt;/a&gt;. Volumes of information in a form even gung-ho IT guys can use when the real engineers aren&amp;rsquo;t around.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0855985348/jrasthought-20&#34;&gt;Transitional Settlement: Displaced Populations&lt;/a&gt;. The overall philosophy of this book is deeply humane, and reflects a quarter century of aid agencies completely screwing up. In addition to making the case for reform in the understanding of migrating people&amp;rsquo;s needs, it also has really cool sample layouts for refugee camps and the various other types of camps you may be called on to set up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/080148796X/jrasthought-20&#34;&gt;Condemned to Repeat?: The Paradox of Humanitarian Action&lt;/a&gt;. Haven&amp;rsquo;t started this one yet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/185339601X/jrasthought-20&#34;&gt;The Humanitarian Companion&lt;/a&gt;. Nuts and bolts things to know, checklists, etc. I haven&amp;rsquo;t read too much of it yet, but the chapter on preparing to deploy was really interesting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0142000221/jrasthought-20&#34;&gt;Cause Celeb&lt;/a&gt;. From the author of Bridget Jones&amp;rsquo;s Diary. Essentially a trashy book for British women to read in the tube on the way to work, except the portrayal of aid worker life and frustrations seems to be very well researched and accurate. The earliest known reference to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.how-matters.org/2011/02/11/missionaries-mercenaries-misfits/&#34;&gt;MMM theory of aid worker motivations&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/1552978656/jrasthought-20&#34;&gt;Hope In Hell: Inside The World Of Doctors Without Borders&lt;/a&gt;. The latest book on MSF. Gives a very good overview of the organization, where it came from, and how it thinks. But if you really want to know the dirt, you have to talk to a returned volunteer. And let me tell you, do you hear dirt&amp;hellip; :)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/1853838799/jrasthought-20&#34;&gt;The Selfish Altruist&lt;/a&gt;. A critique of non-self-aware decision-making by aid agencies, from an experienced and passionate aid worker. His point is we have built in biases, and not paying attention to them results in wrong decisions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A good &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.newyorker.com/reporting/2009/01/05/090105fa_fact_harr?printable=true&#34;&gt;New Yorker article&lt;/a&gt; on life in Chad.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Books I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to get and study, but haven&amp;rsquo;t yet:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Onion knows why I want to work overseas</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2006/03/08/the-onion-knows-why-i-want-to-work-overseas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2006 22:55:44 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=226</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The highly respected journal of international development and humanitarian aid, &lt;em&gt;The Onion&lt;/em&gt;, has &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theonion.com/content/node/45589&#34;&gt;a fascinating article&lt;/a&gt; on relief worker motivations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wink, wink.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt; MSF&amp;rsquo;s own website backs up the Onion&amp;rsquo;s claims. Check out the contents of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.msf.org/source/refbooks/msf_docs/en/Catalog/K/ADM/KADMKLIF08-.pdf&#34;&gt;life support kit for 8 staff members (KADMKLIF08)&lt;/a&gt;. Yeah, there on the third page&amp;hellip; CONDOM, lubricated + RESERVOIR (quantity 144!). Yeah baby&amp;hellip; queue porn music (played on African instruments).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How my talk went</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2006/03/08/how-my-talk-went/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2006 10:50:25 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=225</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My talk on Monday went just fine. It was fun to see people that I&amp;rsquo;d met in Hancock County again, and the hard work I&amp;rsquo;d put in to the supporting documentation paid off. I saw several people reading my report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One interesting thing was that though everyone was dressed in suits
to show proper respect for the proceedings, some people were &amp;ldquo;suits&amp;rdquo;,
and some people were just &amp;ldquo;in suits&amp;rdquo;. There were a whole lot of
vendors there with their hands out trying to sell something. Everyone
could tell within the first few words our of their mouth. What kept it interesting was that both on the panel, and of the invited speakers, there was at least 30%, maybe more, who were just &amp;ldquo;in suits&amp;rdquo;. They were people like me who had real-world experience, didn&amp;rsquo;t care for meetings, or having their time wasted, or getting sales pitches. They were there to make things better, and they didn&amp;rsquo;t have a lot of patience with people who weren&amp;rsquo;t there for the same reason. Very inspiring.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Giving my talk today</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2006/03/06/giving-my-talk-today/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2006 07:58:19 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=224</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m in Jackson, Mississippi today giving my talk on the work Radio Response did in Hancock County. I&amp;rsquo;ve been burning the midnight oil the last few days getting the following documents ready:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nella.org/jra/dr/katrina/jeff-allen-talk.pdf&#34;&gt;The Little Talk&lt;/a&gt; (100 kilobyte PDF file)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nella.org/jra/dr/katrina/report-1.1.pdf&#34;&gt;The Big Report&lt;/a&gt; (2.2 megabyte PDF file)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you find a typo, please don&amp;rsquo;t tell me until next week! I know about the repeated picture, which I&amp;rsquo;ll fix in the next version.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mr. Allen goes to Washington (well, Jackson)</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2006/02/24/mr-allen-goes-to-washington-well-jackson/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2006 19:13:56 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=223</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been invited to give a 10 minute talk about our team&amp;rsquo;s work in Hancock County, Mississippi in front of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fcc.gov/eb/hkip/&#34;&gt;FCC Independent Panel Reviewing the Impact of Hurricane Katrina on Communications Networks&lt;/a&gt;. My talk will be in the afternoon of March 6, in Jackson Mississippi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to drop by if you are in the neighborhood and give me some moral support!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My report on my work after Hurricane Katrina</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2006/02/24/my-report-on-my-work-after-hurricane-katrina/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2006 01:46:25 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=222</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I finally got &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nella.org/jra/dr/katrina/katrina-final-report.html&#34;&gt;my report&lt;/a&gt; done on the lessons I learned while working for &lt;a href=&#34;http://radioresponse.org&#34;&gt;Radio Response&lt;/a&gt; after Hurricane Katrina.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully it will be useful to anyone contemplating starting a group to do work like this.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Screened out</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2006/01/19/screened-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2006 22:57:20 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=221</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I got a letter from MSF today informing me that they have reviewed my application and I won&amp;rsquo;t be getting an interview, and won&amp;rsquo;t be working for them any time soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m disappointed, but not deterred. This simply means I can&amp;rsquo;t get off easy and fill in only one application, as I was hoping to do. I now have a huge amount of work in front of me as I research other organizations and chose some to apply to.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Loneliness</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2006/01/14/loneliness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2006 16:42:15 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=220</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A development worker in Kabul made an &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.livejournal.com/users/vasco_pyjama/126922.html&#34;&gt;interesting post&lt;/a&gt; today. The final paragraph was the most insightful, I thought. And a little bit scary for what it will be like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I started telling people what my goal is, I was afraid they&amp;rsquo;d think I lost my mind. Instead, almost without exception I get good feedback about what I&amp;rsquo;ve set about to do. The other day a woman I really like told me, &amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;re all really proud of you.&amp;rdquo; Which made me feel really good, and made me confident I was on the right track, and I need to keep my eye on the prize and land my first job.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>...and to all a good night</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2005/12/25/and-to-all-a-good-night/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2005 00:10:56 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=217</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve just (barely) beaten my self-imposed deadline of &amp;ldquo;before Christmas&amp;rdquo; for turning in my MSF application. They say that I should hear back from them in 3 or 4 weeks. The next step would be an interview. Don&amp;rsquo;t know how soon it would happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t sent out an update in a while, so here&amp;rsquo;s where I am&amp;hellip; I am visiting my parents in Roseburg, Oregon. While house-sitting in Redwood City during December, I worked a week and a half as a consultant. I also refinished the bathroom of the place I was staying. (Here&amp;rsquo;s where it gets complicated: it was actually the bathroom in a building I partly own, but I was there as a housesitter, not an owner. Get it?) I couldn&amp;rsquo;t mention in my updates that I have been refinishing a bathroom, because it was a surprise gift for Karl (my fellow owner).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The real reason to do humanitarian aid work</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2005/12/16/the-real-reason-to-do-humanitarian-aid-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2005 15:38:06 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=216</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Guys, here&amp;rsquo;s the &lt;a href=&#34;http://sleeplessinsudan.blogspot.com/2005/12/issue-of-men-and-in-particular-lack-of.html&#34;&gt;real reason&lt;/a&gt; to do humanitarian aid work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ladies, fear not, I&amp;rsquo;m on my way, as soon as I get around to putting my MSF application in, and they realize I&amp;rsquo;m the perfect candidate&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seen in the newsletters sent out daily by the Emergency Operations Center</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2005/10/20/seen-in-the-newsletters-sent-out-daily-by-the-emergency-operations-center/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2005 21:02:37 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=205</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Another snippet from the other side of the looking glass:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you need to have a car that you own towed from your property, contact your insurance company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you need to have a car that you &lt;strong&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/strong&gt; own towed from your property, contact a local towing company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you need to have a &lt;strong&gt;house&lt;/strong&gt; that you don&amp;rsquo;t own removed from your property, contact the Army Corps of Engineers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such is the power of 30 feet of salt water driven by a storm 300 miles wide.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Late night thoughts</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2005/10/17/late-night-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2005 23:02:21 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=204</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This afternoon and into the evening I was working on the Waveland water tower. (Yes, on the water tower, 100 feet up.) We put in a long day of debugging in the lab before we went, then working on the tower when we got into the field to install the equipment. So when we got off the tower, I was looking forward to dinner. We&amp;rsquo;d worked too late for dinner at Waveland Cafe, and Don had already declared tonight Pizza Night. We&amp;rsquo;d noticed that the pizzaria had won the &amp;ldquo;first restaurant to reopen&amp;rdquo; contest, and were looking forward to spending a little money in Hancock County. Turns out, it is a lunch place that closes at 4pm, so we missed dinner there. We came back to the completely remodeled Sonic drive-in (complete with girls on skates!) and had dinner. I ordered a large Coke, which might explain why I&amp;rsquo;m wired and not asleep right now.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Live from New Waveland Cafe!</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2005/10/14/live-from-new-waveland-cafe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2005 17:21:21 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=203</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are streaming live music from the New Waveland Cafe over the Radio Response network:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://cbot.tm4h.com:7400/newwavelandcafe.ogg.m3u&#34;&gt;Live from the New Waveland Cafe: Wailin&amp;rsquo; Wally and the Killa Sharks (The Last Band Standing in Waveland)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tune in! (Until 8 or 9 pm, CST).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nearing the end of a long week</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2005/10/11/nearing-the-end-of-a-long-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2005 23:11:11 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=202</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m nearing the &amp;ldquo;end&amp;rdquo; of a long week here. I put &amp;ldquo;end&amp;rdquo; in quotes, because despite my best intentions, my &amp;ldquo;weekends&amp;rdquo; (one day breaks) seem to be separated by increasingly long &amp;ldquo;weeks&amp;rdquo; (my last break was last Monday, so I&amp;rsquo;m only a day late this time, assuming I manage to get away tomorrow, which seems unlikely).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talking about breaks like this sometimes feels indulgent, but when I got here I could see that the project needed some continuity. Since I was in a position to offer some, I decided to take care of myself so as to be able to provide a lot of energy over a long time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New York Times on our work here</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2005/10/05/new-york-times-on-our-work-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2005 09:01:27 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=200</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The New York Times &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2005/10/05/technology/techspecial/05belson.html&#34;&gt;wrote about us&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m in the picture!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Frustrating couple of days</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2005/09/29/frustrating-couple-of-days/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2005 06:03:15 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=199</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The last few days have been the kind of frustrating IT days you can have anywhere. It&amp;rsquo;s just that here I&amp;rsquo;m sleeping in a classroom, showering in a portable shower unit, and eating wilderness fireman food in between the continual IT hassles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As has been observed countless times through history, this job would be OK if it weren&amp;rsquo;t for the customers. They have this expectation that things will &lt;em&gt;work&lt;/em&gt;, and when they don&amp;rsquo;t they come find us and ask us to stop everything and fix our network. Of course, usually we have already noticed that things are broken, and have already stopped everything to work on the broken stuff instead of the new projects we were hoping to get done.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Life in the EOC</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2005/09/21/life-in-the-eoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2005 21:56:45 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=198</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;First, be sure to read the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.radioresponse.org&#34;&gt;Radio Response website&lt;/a&gt;. I am the primary author there, so reading that is as good as reading this. Except there I have to be a bit more professional and circumspect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few days ago I moved to Bay St. Louis. The work was really heating up down here for IT generalists (as they charitably call people who aren&amp;rsquo;t allowed on towers&amp;hellip;). The cynic would also point out that once the Bay St. Louis team&amp;rsquo;s lodgings were upgraded to include air conditioning I consented to go to Bay St. Louis.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Superfast update</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2005/09/19/superfast-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2005 08:41:27 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=197</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Super-fast update, since I am in the middle of stuff here, but also realized I haven&amp;rsquo;t written in a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have visited Bay St. Louis. The destruction there is incredible. I have not seen the water front, just the wind and flood damage several hundred yards inland. Our team is kicking butt here, but it just takes so much longer to get things done than you can possibly imagine. It&amp;rsquo;s frustrating, but we won&amp;rsquo;t give up. It&amp;rsquo;s no one&amp;rsquo;s fault. We are now tied into the systems here so that we are no longer being actively prevented from working by the authorities. Now it&amp;rsquo;s simply a complex situation, and you have to work around problems one at a time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First full day</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2005/09/16/first-full-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2005 06:06:29 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=196</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I worked my first full day. So I&amp;rsquo;ve been at work 1.5 days. In that time, two new people have come in. I made a minimal system to get people up and running, and tried it out on the next two after me. I suspect that as I start working in the field it wil fall by the wayside, but at lesat two people know what new people should get told.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 1</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2005/09/15/day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2005 06:58:13 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=195</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My first day was half a day because I got here and got put to work after noon. I spent the first while getting the lay of the land, the people, etc. The Bay St. Louis team was getting loaded up to head south, so there was some work to do there. Once they left it calmed down quite a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I identified two needs and a guy named Alecs and I self-organized into a little team to chip away at them. We need a single public website, and also a single internal place for a couple web apps people have thrown together with Ruby on Rails. We could also use a better &amp;ldquo;new volunteer arrives and gets to work&amp;rdquo; process. So those are the things I am working on.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Arrived in Ponchatoula</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2005/09/14/arrived-in-ponchatoula/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2005 13:22:47 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=194</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I arrived in Ponchatoula a little while ago. I can tell I am going to like working with these guys. The trick now is to find a job and start doing it. I think perhaps I will start the same way I did in Guatemala, by drawing a network diagram of the staging area here so that I know how things work (and so that the next guy knows too).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>With Cliff in Dallas</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2005/09/13/with-cliff-in-dallas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2005 23:36:55 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=193</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I dropped in on &lt;a href=&#34;http://cliffmccarthy.net/&#34;&gt;Cliff McCarthy&lt;/a&gt; in Dallas for the night. Cliff and I enjoyed dinner and chatting, then a big shopping trip at Walmart. Came in way under budget on food and water, so either I am going to starve, or I was being pessimistic when I budgeted. Cliff reminded me that not only is everything bigger in Texas, but everything is cheaper too. Which might explain why every &lt;strong&gt;one&lt;/strong&gt; in Texas is bigger too!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Flagstaff</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2005/09/12/flagstaff/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2005 20:32:45 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=192</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am in Flagstaff right now. I will have dinner here, then hit the road to get another hour of progress eastward then bed down for the night. I will hit the road again at dawn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Random data from the road: gas in Bakersfield was 3.35. The higest I saw was 3.65, on the border with CA and AZ. On the AZ side of the border the gas was $2.99. It is inconceiveable to me that within 10 miles the price changed by 66 cents!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leaving Redwod City</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2005/09/12/leaving-redwod-city/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2005 07:01:04 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=191</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Leaving Redwood City about 7:15 am. Next stop, Albuquerque.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Change of Plans, again</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2005/09/11/change-of-plans-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2005 10:39:06 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=190</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten in touch with some great guys who are installing WiFi in shelters in Louisiana, and have decided to make a trip out there in my car to work with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being outside the Palo Alto area will likely disrupt my attempts to get placed with Red Cross, so I plan to drop by the Red Cross office today and have them stop my application from going onwards. When I check in to the farm where I will be staying in LA, I will also check in with the Red Cross there and let them know that if/when it makes sense for me to transition from tech work to shelter work, I&amp;rsquo;m ready to do so.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
