<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Economy on jra&#39;s thoughts</title>
    <link>https://blog.nella.org/category/economy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Economy on jra&#39;s thoughts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.147.8</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 May 2009 14:54:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.nella.org/category/economy/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Community Finance in West Africa</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2009/05/08/community-finance-in-west-africa/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2009 14:54:10 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=675</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Vasco Pyjama &lt;a href=&#34;http://vasco-pyjama.livejournal.com/233192.html&#34;&gt;talks about community finance&lt;/a&gt;. The ROSCA is known as a &amp;ldquo;sou-sou&amp;rdquo; in west Africa, or at least in Nimba county, Liberia. Sousous run for a fixed term, based on the number of members. If there are 10 members and the contribution is $10, each month one of the members will get $90 (9 other members * $10 each). At the end of ten months, the sousou can either be restarted, or the membership can be renegotiated (for example, to drop people who failed to pay on time during the past sousou period). If the sousou is reconstituted with more or fewer people, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t really change anything, it just runs shorter or longer until the next restart. Sousous run best when they are between 6 and 12 people for social and economic reasons (a 5x - 11x payoff is manageable in a cash society). The order of the payouts is determined randomly at the startup meeting of the sousou. Sometimes people negotiate to trade their places in the payout order in order to assure that the sousou payout would arrive at a time that was convenient for them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fishy Accounting Business</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2009/04/27/fishy-accounting-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2009 13:30:57 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=663</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Listen to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.npr.org/blogs/money/2009/04/hear_shadow_banking.html&#34;&gt;this Planet Money episode&lt;/a&gt;, it&amp;rsquo;s got a really clear example of how banks are allowed to book profits based on people &lt;em&gt;losing confidence&lt;/em&gt; in them. It&amp;rsquo;s really mind bending, and shows two things: one, how the finance industry is a hall of mirrors, and two, how talented Planet Money is at breaking down the mirrors. Keep up the good work guys, when is the Pulitzer prize coming?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Economics of being a Hostage</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2009/04/23/the-economics-of-being-a-hostage/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2009 19:50:26 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=644</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s an incredible &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.npr.org/blogs/money/2009/04/pirates_have_timesheets.html&#34;&gt;inside view of the piracy business&lt;/a&gt;. What&amp;rsquo;s incredible is that NPR&amp;rsquo;s Channa Jaffe Walt managed to get a CEO of a shipping company on the phone and hear the inside story of the negotiations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what&amp;rsquo;s really interesting. The first thing the CEO says is, &amp;ldquo;I never thought for a moment that I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have to pay anything. The only question was how much, and when.&amp;rdquo; Channa asks him why and he says, &amp;ldquo;Look, there&amp;rsquo;s no one to turn to, we&amp;rsquo;re on our own out there and that&amp;rsquo;s all there is to it. You pay.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heard in Europe</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2009/04/20/heard-in-europe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2009 16:08:14 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=643</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Overheard here in England (which was, last I checked, a European country):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found a really interesting partnership we could join, but we&amp;rsquo;d have to make friends with a bunch of Europeans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Insert sound of my jaw dropping the floor here&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Repair vs Replace</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2009/04/10/repair-vs-replace/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2009 07:56:47 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=632</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What are the economic effects of the repair vs replace decision? Interesting question, that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you missed &amp;ldquo;more local employment of the blue collar type&amp;rdquo;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.npr.org/blogs/money/2009/04/repair_beats_replace.html&#34;&gt;go read this&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a slight diversion of purchasing strategy, repair rather than replace. This feeds a blue collar industry in the local region.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It used to be, when money was loose, replace with new was the norm. If the repair was 75 percent of the cost of replacement a new motor was ordered, the old motor was scraped, and the country of origin (Mexico, China, Taiwan) benefited. These beautiful USA built, 50 year old, 200 horsepower motors, were going to the scrap heap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Savior</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2009/03/31/the-savior/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2009 02:04:52 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=614</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Check out the image at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/09/03/30/GM-and-Chrysler/&#34;&gt;bottom of this post&lt;/a&gt;. Obama with a halo. Cute.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My favorite things, all at once!</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2009/03/31/my-favorite-things-all-at-once/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2009 00:07:38 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=608</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yay for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.caida.org/~kc/&#34;&gt;old friends&lt;/a&gt;, economics, and technology! All at once!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;kc wrote a &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.caida.org/best_available_data/2009/03/29/icannrir-research-agenda-writ-large/&#34;&gt;blog posting with her humble ideas&lt;/a&gt; on how to use IP address space tax. Wait&amp;hellip; there&amp;rsquo;s a tax on address space? Yes, because it has become a scare quantity, because people are too lazy to move to IPv6, IPv4 address space is running out. The best of all bad ideas about what to do about this is to make an open market for address space, as though network addresses were some kind of useful piece of property with any kind of useful value. (BTW: When the present econolypse is over, and the next bubble starts, it will be an IPv4 address space bubble. Mark my words&amp;hellip;) Address space is bits. We can make more bits&amp;hellip; Look! I just made some! But because the value of a network exists in everyone who is using it, not just &lt;strong&gt;your&lt;/strong&gt; implementation of the network, you can&amp;rsquo;t just add bits in your IP stack and get any benefit. So, while bits are free, and address space could conceiveably be free, because we have a network with limited space, we have a scarce asset. And, of course, what do humans do with scarce assets? We make bubbles! Yay for bubbles!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Negative Feedback</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2009/03/28/negative-feedback/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2009 18:22:17 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=604</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Planet Money is talking about the new Systemic Regulator, and also talking about other theoretical ways of regulating the banks. It occurs to me that one thing that&amp;rsquo;s missing, and not just a little bit missing, but radically missing, from the current system is negative feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t it be interesting if we could set things up so that before the next bubble starts, the participants in the market can see that as certain stages of the bubble kick in, as measured by certain predetermined checkpoints, then certain economic brakes will be applied. We&amp;rsquo;d have to be careful not to take away all the control the Fed has, but perhaps you can invent a new set of levers which fall into this category of automatically triggered negative feedback.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Twin Peaks</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2009/03/02/twin-peaks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2009 16:38:25 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=567</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.npr.org/blogs/money/2009/02/household_debt_vs_gdp.html&#34;&gt;scariest evidence&lt;/a&gt; yet that this recession is not a normal one:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;graph&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://media.npr.org/blogs/globalpoolofmoney/images/2009/02/hh.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was brought to my attention by an excellent This American Life &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thisamericanlife.org/Radio_Episode.aspx?episode=375&#34;&gt;episode&lt;/a&gt;. The conclusion of Alex and Adam&amp;rsquo;s story at the top of the program is chilling&amp;hellip; there&amp;rsquo;s several ways to read the tea leaves, and none of them are very good.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Secret of the Economics of Manufacturing</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2009/02/27/a-secret-of-the-economics-of-manufacturing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2009 14:01:27 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=561</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I saw this quote in an &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.xconomy.com/boston/2009/02/26/kindling-a-revolution-e-inks-russ-wilcox-on-e-paper-amazon-and-the-future-of-publishing&#34;&gt;article on E-Ink&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you ever want to make a billion of anything cheaply, you print it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What an interesting observation! With such interesting far reaching consequences:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nanosolar.com/&#34;&gt;Nano Solar&lt;/a&gt; is on the right track, crystaline solar is not.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Diamond_Age&#34;&gt;Diamond Age&lt;/a&gt;-style nano-assembly is not quite a sure bet, and mass-customization by &lt;a href=&#34;http://fab.cba.mit.edu/&#34;&gt;table-top fabs&lt;/a&gt; will clearly never be able to compete on price with items that are printed. Though another way of looking at nano-assembly is to recognize that nature manufactures far more, far cheaper, than all the printing presses in the world&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Things that are flat, flexible, and where the complexity is expressed in 2D will always be cheaper than their competitors which violate one of those constraints of printing presses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also further informs my &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.nella.org/?p=448&#34;&gt;day dreaming about clay tablets&lt;/a&gt;: a system for preserving data needs to be flat, flexible, and 2D. My &amp;ldquo;dots on ceramic&amp;rdquo; design might still be able to fit the bill, but the kind of uber-cheap ceramic I was thinking of (i.e. the same stuff in the 20 cent porcelin plates at Ikea) won&amp;rsquo;t be the material, something else will be. But what? What can go roll-to-roll in a printing press environment, but has the chemical stability of ceramics? I&amp;rsquo;m feeling like I really wish there was a layman&amp;rsquo;s introduction to ceramics on my reading list right now. Anyone? Anyone? Bueller?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The power of debt</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2009/01/22/the-power-of-debt/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2009 02:33:38 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=518</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a quote that turns everything you think you know on it&amp;rsquo;s head:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the debt is big enough, it&amp;rsquo;s the debtor who has the power, not the creditor.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vanityfair.com/online/politics/2009/01/niall-ferguson-america-needs-to-cancel-its-debt.html&#34;&gt;Niall Ferguson talking in Vanity Fair&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s for stuff like that I read Vanity Fair. Well, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vanityfair.com/culture/features/2009/02/cate-blanchett-slideshow200902?slide=18&#34;&gt;photos&lt;/a&gt; don&amp;rsquo;t hurt either&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Interview with a DVD-man</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2008/11/15/an-interview-with-a-dvd-man/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2008 16:54:34 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=429</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Rare is the dinner in an expat restaurant in Africa which is not (politely and quietly) interrupted by a DVD-man. They have a stock of DVD&amp;rsquo;s in their backpacks, and work their way through the restaurant giving you a chance to peruse their wares. You have to see the DVDs to believe them, they are made up of several pirated Hollywood movies, with many different versions, all on one disc, enclosed in a professional-looking full color envelope. They have titles like &amp;ldquo;Segal vs Chan&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip; a DVD full of Steve Segal and Jackie Chan movies. Another great title is &amp;ldquo;Superhero Schoolwork&amp;rdquo;, including Spiderman, Superman, and Wonderwoman (and all the sequels thereof). The DVD&amp;rsquo;s are billed as &amp;ldquo;50 in one&amp;rdquo;, though it requires some clever counting to find 50 movies on one disc. Typically, there are more like 12 movies on a DVD &amp;ndash; in itself an impressive achievement of DVD mastering and compression-algorithm optimization.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A message...</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2008/11/05/a-message/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2008 15:54:22 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=424</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;from America, reaching out to every corner of the globe, into the hearts of those who have watched us struggle and fail to meet our potential over the last 8 years:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes We Can!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like a drug-addled celebrity, we&amp;rsquo;ve hit &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/George_W._Bush&#34;&gt;rock bottom&lt;/a&gt;, and now we&amp;rsquo;re ready to turn our lives around and meet our potential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, if you will excuse me, I&amp;rsquo;m going to go celebrate the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Guy_Fawkes_Night&#34;&gt;near destruction of the English parliament&lt;/a&gt;. (Guy Falkes was clearly a democrat.) Another example of why England is backwards: normal people rejoice at the idea of blowing up their corrupt and greedy legislatures. Bonfire night is unfortunately apparently about celebrating that the plot was &lt;strong&gt;foiled!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Economic Meltdown in Iceland</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2008/10/31/economic-meltdown-in-iceland/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2008 14:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=411</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&#34;http://groups.google.com/group/geekup/browse_thread/thread/0754965a91630114#&#34;&gt;this thread&lt;/a&gt; on a local geek social group in Leeds. That&amp;rsquo;s the voice of one scared girl, and perhaps the reality is not so bad. But just the fact that there is one Icelander who&amp;rsquo;s feeling that freaked out makes my heart go out to her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve suggested to her that one problem is translations, and that she could earn some hard currency by starting a blog with translations of the articles describing the meltdown and then putting a &lt;a href=&#34;http://tipjoy.com&#34;&gt;TipJoy&lt;/a&gt; widget on it. I&amp;rsquo;d pay to hear the voice of Iceland from inside, instead of mediated by the Mainstream Media.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why doesn&#39;t this already exist?</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2008/10/25/why-doesnt-this-already-exist/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2008 18:43:17 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=399</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I was walking in town and there was a nice guy playing a clarinet in front of North Face. I intentionally fumbled with my coins for a while so as to enjoy his music a bit. Then I paid him a tip and walked along, enjoying the clarinet as it faded behind me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why can&amp;rsquo;t I do that for the gigabytes of copyright violations I illegally download? (Note to RIAA lawyers: this is a hypothetical situation. No need to sue me. Thanks.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Big Mining Machines</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2008/10/20/big-mining-machines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2008 12:25:24 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=379</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Long Now foundation &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.longnow.org/2008/10/09/our-lust-for-metal-is-great/&#34;&gt;took a field trip&lt;/a&gt; recently. The pictures are cool, as is the irony that they went to a trade show held once every four years. Miners have a time scale closer to the Long Now&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does it mean that mining is a slowly changing industry? The economics of extractive industries push them that direction (capital investment is only warranted by a positive outlook in the commodity price). But workplace safety, which is a special case of universal human rights, demands that &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.coalminingsafety.org/&#34;&gt;industries take advantage&lt;/a&gt; of the best available technology as fast as possible. This is an interesting story of the tension between capitalism and social welfare. If a mining regulator pushes an industry too much it will give up and move elsewhere. And apparently the mining industry is especially prone to &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Regulatory_capture&#34;&gt;regulatory capture&lt;/a&gt; an euphemism for corruption I especially like (like as in hate; in newspeak up is down, enslaved is free and corruption is regulatory capture).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Market Goes &#34;Underground&#34;</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2008/10/16/the-market-goes-underground/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2008 14:10:18 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=371</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a lesson about social policies, politics and economics. In Gaza, &lt;a href=&#34;http://news.bbc.co.uk/2/hi/middle_east/7673926.stm&#34;&gt;tunnels used for smuggling goods have become the major supply line, and an industry in themselves.&lt;/a&gt; The market will provide, it will always provide. The question is, how do you use the power of the market to get the other results you want?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this case, it is pretty clear to me that be blockading Gaza on the Israeli border, the Israeli authorities have lost their capacity to control smuggling, not to mention lost tons of tax revenue and economic activity for Israeli businessmen. Clearly, Not Plan A.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Banks: You&#39;re Under New Management... Listen Up!</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2008/10/14/banks-youre-under-new-management-listen-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2008 23:24:20 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=369</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A wonderful &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.owen.org/blog/95&#34; title=&#34;open letter&#34;&gt;open letter&lt;/a&gt; from a fellow stockholder to our new investment&amp;rsquo;s board of directors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If only it were so easy&amp;hellip; This is what justice would look like in a society that craved social justice and capitalism in equal parts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21 words that should change your life (but probably won&#39;t)</title>
      <link>https://blog.nella.org/2008/10/09/21-words-that-should-change-your-life-but-probably-wont/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2008 09:05:01 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.nella.org/?p=341</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Clarity on what&amp;rsquo;s wrong with our economy and our society, and advice on how to correct it, all in just 3 lines, and 21 words:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You buy things and you don&amp;rsquo;t need.
With money that you don&amp;rsquo;t have.
To impress people that you don&amp;rsquo;t even like.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From Aaron Stewart, &amp;quot; &lt;a href=&#34;http://aaronstewart.blogspot.com/2008/10/our-economic-woes-in-three-lines.html&#34;&gt;Our economic woes in three lines&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
